Jessie Lloyd O'Connor Papers, 1850-1988
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- SERIES III. WRITINGS 1889-1989
  - Articles and essays
    - Alphabetical by subject
      - Russia
        - Financial and legal material (in Russian)1927-38, undated (Box 91, Folder 7)
      - Spain1936, undated (Box 91, Folder 8)
      - Surveys1938, undated (Box 91, Folder 9)
      - Travel
        - General: notes, diaries, printed material, and typescripts about Argentina, Bolivia, Mexico, Jamaica, and Appalachia1931, 1950, 1958-70, undated (Box 92, Folder 1)
        - Notes and printed material
          - Cubaundated (Box 92, Folder 2)
          - Egyptundated (Box 92, Folder 3)
          - Mexicoundated (Box 92, Folder 4)
          - Yugoslavia1951, 1957 (Box 92, Folder 5-6)
      - Unidentified authors (some possibly by JLO) (Box 92, Folder 7)
      - United Nations petitionundated (Box 92, Folder 8)
      - Vietnam: drafts of articles, notes, and self-published brochure "The War in Vietnam Why?" (n.d.)1965-77, undated (Box 92, Folder 9)
      - Volya (yacht): drafts of articles, self-published pamphlet, diary, and correspondence1954-57, undated (Box 92, Folder 10)
      - Wallace, Henry, campaign: writings and speechescirca 1948 (Box 92, Folder 11)
        [see also SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES--Progressive Party; and SERIES V. SUBJECT FILES -Political campaigns]
      - War profiteers: typescript fragmentsundated (Box 92, Folder 12)
      - Welfare, Pennsylvania: interview and notescirca 1932 (Box 92, Folder 13)
      - World constitutional convention: flyer, press release, and notescirca 1945 (Box 92, Folder 14)
  - Speeches
    - Correspondence and texts1936-57, undated (Box 92, Folder 15)
    - Notesundated (Box 92, Folder 16)
  - London Daily Herald
    - Correspondence1926-27, undated (Box 93, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence and writings in French1926-27 (Box 93, Folder 2)
    - Articles: drafts1926-27 (Box 93, Folder 3)
    - Clippings (by JLO and others)1927 (Box 93, Folder 4)
    - League of Nations conference, Geneva: conference materials, clippings, and notes1927 (Box 93, Folder 5-7)
    - Miscellaneous printed material1926-27, undated (Box 93, Folder 8)
  - Federated Press
    [see also SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE-Friends and associates- Haessler, Carl and Lucy; and Seibel, Jule]
    - General
      - Clippings, press releases, and drafts1930-45, undated (Box 93, Folder 9)
      - Correspondence1928-56, 1987-88, undated (Box 93, Folder 10)
    - Gastonia, NC, 1929-30
      - By JLO: articles, press releases, pamphlet (Gastonia, a Graphic Chapter In Southern Organization (1930)), drafts, and printed material1929-30, undated (Box 93, Folder 11)
      - Articles by others (includes Margaret Larkin of FP)1929, undated (Box 93, Folder 12)
    - North and South Carolina, including Marion Manufacturing strikecirca 1929
      [see also SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL-Photographs--Sites, scenes, and subjects]
      - Press releases (Box 93, Folder 13)
      - Clippings (Box 93, Folder 14)
    - Southern prisons: correspondence, articles, clippings, and research material1928-30 (Box 94, Folder 1)
    - Soviet flight to U.S.: Article ("15,000 View Soviet Flight Finish," Labor News, 9 Nov 1929), drafts, and research material1929, undated (Box 94, Folder 2)
    - Harlan, KY miners' strike
      - Biographical material: articles about JLO1931-32, undated (Box 94, Folder 3)
        [see also SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL -Articles and interviews-Articles about]
      - Correspondence
        - Threatening letter1931 (Box 94, Folder 3a)
        - Jessie and Harvey O'Connor1931-32, undated (Box 94, Folder 4)
        - Fundraising appeal and draftscirca 1932 (Box 94, Folder 5)
      - Writings
        - Articles, press releases, and drafts1931-32, undated (Box 94, Folder 6)
        - Notes (includes interview notes)undated (Box 94, Folder 7-9)
        - Press releases by other FP reporters1931-32, undated (Box 94, Folder 10)
        - Research files, 1931-32, undated
          - General (Box 94, Folder 11-12)
          - Harlan opinion, union and anti-union (Box 94, Folder 13)
          - Murder trials and free speech fight (Box 94, Folder 14)
          - Tennessee NMU organizing campaign (Box 94, Folder 15)
          - Writers Committee beating (Box 94, Folder 16)
          - "Speech" [?] (Box 94, Folder 17)
          - Trials-William Hightower (Box 94, Folder 18)
          - Strike (Box 94, Folder 19)
          - Freedom of the press (Box 95, Folder 1)
          - William Burnett and William Jones (Box 95, Folder 2)
          - Governor's report (Box 95, Folder 3)
          - Economic conditions (Box 95, Folder 4)
          - Miners' trials (Box 95, Folder 5)
          - Theodore Dreiser's visit and indictment (Box 95, Folder 6)
        - Printed material and memorabiliacirca 1931-32 (Box 95, Folder 7)
    - Pennsylvania, 1931-35
      - Pittsburgh
        [see also SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL--Photographs-- Sites, scenes, and subjects]
        - Press releases and drafts1931-35, undated (Box 95, Folder 8)
        - Newspaper clippingscirca 1934 (Box 95, Folder 9)
        - Research material1931, 1933, undated (Box 95, Folder 10)
        - Notesundated (Box 95, Folder 11)
      - Mine strikes
        - Articles, press releases, drafts, and interview notes1931[?]-34, undated (Box 95, Folder 12)
        - Correspondence, notes (including interviews), and research material1931-34, undated (Box 95, Folder 13)
        - Newspaper clippings (includes article about JLO)1933-34 (Box 95, Folder 14)
      - William Penn and Fort Pitt Hotel strike: correspondence, notes, writings, printed material1933-34 (Box 95, Folder 15)
    - Harvester strike, Chicago: press release, statement and printed material1941, undated (Box 95, Folder 16)
    - Memorabilia: press passes, printed material about FP, lists (including abbreviations used on clippings)1939-56, undated (Box 95, Folder 17)
  - Memoirs
    - Contumacious Couple: Memoirs of Harvey and Jessie O'Connor (typescript), 1985
      - Drafts (Box 95, Folder 18-19)
      - Drafts (Box 96, Folder 1-6)
      - Drafts (Box 97, Folder 1)
      - Final text (Box 97, Folder 2-9)
      - Research notes1978, undated (Box 98, Folder 1)
      - Readers' evaluations (Box 98, Folder 2)
    - Harvey and Jessie: A Couple of Radicals by Harvey and Jessie Lloyd O'Connor, and Susan Bowler (Temple University Press: Philadelphia), 1988
      - Correspondence1983-89, undated (Box 98, Folder 3)
      - Drafts (Box 98, Folder 4-9)
      - Drafts (Box 99, Folder 1-7)
      - Final copy (Box 99, Folder 8-9)
      - Corrected final copy (Box 100, Folder 1-5)
      - Galley proofs (forward and preface only) (Box 100, Folder 6)
      - Reviews1988-89 (Box 100, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous printed material and notes (Box 100, Folder 8)
    - Computer disks (Box 100, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous notes and research material
    - 1920s (Box 101, Folder 1)
    - "Very personal notes and musical themes from 1928-29 & speech notes from Commencement 1930 (June 15) day before wedding" (Box 101, Folder 2)
    - 1930s (Box 101, Folder 3)
    - 1940s (Box 101, Folder 4)
    - 1950s (Box 101, Folder 5-9)
    - 1960-67 (Box 101, Folder 10-11)
    - 1968-69 (Box 102, Folder 1)
    - 1970s (Box 102, Folder 2)
    - Undated (Box 102, Folder 3-10)
    - Undated (Box 103, Folder 1-2)
    - Antifascismundated (Box 103, Folder 3)
    - Boncour, Paul ("For Paul Boncour")undated (Box 103, Folder 4)
    - Chicago steel strike riot1937 (Box 103, Folder 5)
    - Civil liberties1938, undated (Box 103, Folder 6)
    - German-Americans1939, undated (Box 103, Folder 7)
    - Historical quotes (Box 103, Folder 8)
    - Housing
      - Generalcirca 1940, undated (Box 103, Folder 9)
      - Chicago housing filmcirca 1940 (Box 103, Folder 10)
    - Ideas for writings1942, 1946, 1972, undated (Box 103, Folder 11)
    - Religious organizationsundated (Box 103, Folder 12)
    - Seattle and the Northwestundated (Box 103, Folder 13)
    - Steel industry, Pittsburghcirca 1930s (Box 103, Folder 14)
    - War tax resistance1972, undated (Box 103, Folder 15)
    - Welfareundated (Box 103, Folder 16)
    - Winnetka (includes Edison takeover of Winnetka power plant)undated (Box 103, Folder 17)
    - World governmentundated (Box 103, Folder 18)
  - By other family
    - Green, Rena Maverick1932-36, undated (Box 104, Folder 1)
    - Lloyd, Georgia1945, 1952, undated (Box 104, Folder 2)
      [see also SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES-Campaign for World Government]
    - Lloyd, Henry Demarest1894, 1902-03, 1948, 1952 (Box 104, Folder 3)
    - Lloyd, Henry Demarest, Jr.circa 1889 (Box 104, Folder 4)
    - Lloyd, John Bird1943, undated (Box 104, Folder 5)
    - Lloyd, Lola Maverick1910-42, undated (Box 104, Folder 6)
    - Lloyd, Mary1924, 1932, 1962-63, undated (Box 104, Folder 7)
    - Lloyd, William, Sr.1935, 1942-43, undated (Box 104, Folder 8)
    - Lloyd, William, Jr.
      - General1934-86, undated (Box 104, Folder 9)
      - Toward Freedom: A Newsletter on Colonial Affairs (editor)1956-84 (Box 104, Folder 10)
    - Maverick, Lewis1955, 1970, undated (Box 104, Folder 11)
    - Maverick, Maury, Sr.1935-54, undated (Box 104, Folder 12)
    - Maverick, Maury, Jr.1966-88, undated (Box 104, Folder 13)
    - O'Connor, Harvey1927-80, undated (Box 104, Folder 14)
    - O'Connor, Steven1960, 1972, undated (Box 104, Folder 15)
    - Strobell, Caro Lloyd1939, undated (Box 104, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous family (Box 104, Folder 17)
- SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES 1918-1988
  - Abraham Lincoln School
    - Correspondence1943-46 (Box 105, Folder 1)
    - Printed materialcirca 1942-45 (Box 105, Folder 2)
  - Action for World Federation1946, undated (Box 105, Folder 3)
  - Affiliated School for Workers (later known as American Labor Education Service)1937-62, undated (Box 105, Folder 4)
  - Africa Defense and Aid Fund1960, 1970, undated (Box 105, Folder 5)
  - Altgeld Centenary Committee of Illinois1947 (Box 105, Folder 6)
  - Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union1947-51, undated (Box 105, Folder 7)
  - Amalgamated Meat Cutters and Butcher Workmen of North America1972, undated (Box 105, Folder 8)
  - American Association of University Women
    - Correspondence and notes1937-52, undated (Box 105, Folder 9)
    - Printed material1947-50 (Box 105, Folder 10)
  - American Bureau for Medical Aid to China1940-51 (Box 105, Folder 11)
  - American Civil Liberties Union
    - Correspondence1931-87, undated (Box 105, Folder 12)
    - Illinois affiliate1956-69 (Box 105, Folder 13)
    - Rhode Island affiliate1960-68, undated (Box 105, Folder 14)
    - Wisconsin affiliate1973-74, undated (Box 105, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous affiliates1931, 1968, 1977, undated (Box 105, Folder 16)
    - Printed material1924-68, undated (Box 105, Folder 17)
    - Lists1933, undated (Box 105, Folder 18)
  - American Committee for Industrial Cooperatives1982 (Box 105, Folder 19)
  - American Committee for Protection of the Foreign Born
    - Correspondence1953-57 (Box 106, Folder 1)
    - Printed material1939-66, undated (Box 106, Folder 2-3)
  - American Committee on Africa1955-72, undated (Box 106, Folder 4)
  - American Congress for Peace and Democracy1939 (Box 106, Folder 5)
  - American Council for a Democratic Greece1947-48, undated (Box 106, Folder 6)
  - American Federation of Labor1942, 1954, undated (Box 106, Folder 7)
  - American Forum for Socialist Education1957 (Box 106, Folder 8)
  - American Freedom of Residence Fund1961-63, undated (Box 106, Folder 9)
  - American Friends Service Committee
    - Correspondence1944-88, undated (Box 106, Folder 10)
    - Chicago Regional Office1942-72, undated (Box 106, Folder 11)
    - New England Regional Office1951-72, undated (Box 106, Folder 12)
    - Rhode Island Area Office1973-88, undated (Box 106, Folder 13)
    - Texas Office1946, undated (Box 106, Folder 14)
    - Printed material1951-72, undated (Box 107, Folder 1)
  - American/Rhode Island Humanist Association1941-72, undated (Box 107, Folder 2)
  - American League against War and Fascism
    [see also SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE--McKibben, R. Norman]
    - Correspondence1934-38, undated (Box 107, Folder 3)
    - Clippings1934-37 (Box 107, Folder 4)
    - Meeting materials
      - General1934-37 (Box 107, Folder 5)
      - Western Pennsylvania Conference against War and FascismNov 1935 (Box 107, Folder 6)
    - Notes and writings1935-36, undated (Box 107, Folder 7)
    - Printed material1920s-37, undated (Box 107, Folder 8)
    - Resolutions and statements1935-37, undated (Box 107, Folder 9)
  - American League for Peace and Democracy1937-44, undated (Box 107, Folder 10)
  - American Peace Mobilization1940-41, undated (Box 107, Folder 11)
  - American Protestant Defense League1950-51 (Box 108, Folder 1)
  - American Security Council1971 (Box 108, Folder 2)
  - American Socialist1955-57, undated (Box 108, Folder 3)
  - American Society to Defend Children1966-67 (Box 108, Folder 4)
  - American Unitarian Association/Unitarian Church1943-64, undated (Box 108, Folder 5)
  - American Veterans Committee1948, undated (Box 108, Folder 6)
  - American Youth Congress1938-40, undated (Box 108, Folder 7)
  - Americans for Democratic Action1949-72, undated (Box 108, Folder 8)
  - Amnesty International1961-84, undated (Box 108, Folder 9)
  - Another Mother for Peace1967-72, undated (Box 108, Folder 10)
  - Appalachian Committee for Full Employment1964-65 (Box 108, Folder 11)
  - Appalachian South Folklife Center1968-81, undated (Box 108, Folder 12)
  - L'assembleé Constituante des Peuples1959-60 (Box 108, Folder 13)
  - Association for Research and Enlightenment1937-45, undated (Box 108, Folder 14)
    [see also SERIES V. SUBJECT FILES-Cayce, Edgar]
  - Association for Union Democracy1973-84 (Box 108, Folder 15)
  - Association on American Indian Affairs1962-73, undated (Box 108, Folder 16)
  - Audubon Society of Rhode Island1953-73, undated (Box 108, Folder 17)
  - A1918-88, undated (Box 109, Folder 1)
  - Bahai1950-55 (Box 109, Folder 2)
  - Boston Clamshellcirca 1970s (Box 109, Folder 3)
  - British Peace Committee1964-66, undated (Box 109, Folder 4)
  - B1940-70 (Box 109, Folder 5)
  - Cambridge Instituteundated (Box 109, Folder 6)
  - Campaign for a World Constitution/World Committee for a World Constitutional Convention1952-68, undated (Box 109, Folder 7)
  - Campaign for Disarmament1960, undated (Box 109, Folder 8)
  - Campaign for World Government, Inc.
    [see also SERIES III. WRITINGS-By other family-Lloyd, Georgia]
    - Correspondence1940-75, undated (Box 109, Folder 9)
    - Printed material1938-86, undated (Box 109, Folder 10)
  - CARE1949-62, undated (Box 109, Folder 11)
  - Center for Constitutional Rights1973-88 (Box 109, Folder 12)
  - Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions1960-66 (Box 110, Folder 1)
  - Central Committee for Conscientious Objectors
    - Correspondence1953-85, undated (Box 110, Folder 2)
    - "News Notes" 1957-74, undated (Box 110, Folder 3)
  - Chicago Civil Liberties Committee
    - Correspondence1938-1944 (Box 110, Folder 4)
    - Printed material1937-42, undated (Box 110, Folder 5)
  - Chicago Committee of Russian War Relief1942-44, undated (Box 110, Folder 6)
  - Chicago Committee to Defend the Bill of Rights1962-69, undated (Box 110, Folder 7)
  - Chicago Committee to Oppose Peacetime Conscription1945-48, undated (Box 110, Folder 8)
  - Chicago Council Against Racial and Religious Discrimination1947-51, undated (Box 110, Folder 9)
  - Chicago Council of American/Soviet Friendship1944-57, undated (Box 110, Folder 10)
  - Chicago Urban League1944-45, undated (Box 110, Folder 11)
  - China Welfare Appeal1951-54, undated (Box 110, Folder 12)
  - Church of Christ1932-49 (Box 110, Folder 13)
  - Churchman Associates1952-58 (Box 110, Folder 14)
  - Citizens Committee for Constitutional Liberties1960s, undated (Box 110, Folder 15)
  - Citizens Committee for Harry Bridges1941-42, undated (Box 110, Folder 16)
    [see also SERIES V. SUBJECT FILES--Bridges, Harry]
  - Citizens Committee for Price Control1944 (Box 110, Folder 17)
  - Citizens Committee on Displaced Persons1947-49, undated (Box 110, Folder 18)
  - Citizens Committee on Industrial Relations1939-40 (Box 110, Folder 19)
  - Citizens Committee to Preserve American Freedoms1955-62, undated (Box 110, Folder 20)
  - Citizens Concerned for Peace1951 (Box 110, Folder 21)
  - Citizens Emergency Committee on Industrial Relations1938 (Box 110, Folder 22)
  - Citizens Emergency Defense Conference1952-54, undated (Box 110, Folder 23)
  - Citizens Exchange Corps1966 (Box 110, Folder 24)
  - Citizens Party of Rhode Island1982-83, undated (Box 110, Folder 25)
  - Citizens Planning and Housing Association of Baltimore1948-50 (Box 110, Folder 26)
  - Citizens Schools Committee1938, undated (Box 111, Folder 1)
  - Civil Liberties Union of Massachusetts1949-51 (Box 111, Folder 2)
  - Civil Rights Congress1946-55, undated (Box 111, Folder 3)
  - Claude Williams Support Committee
    [see also SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE--Friends and associates--Douglas, Scott, and Williams, Claude and Joyce; and SERIES V. SUBJECT FILES--Williams, Claude]
    - Correspondence1954-77 (Box 111, Folder 4)
    - Printed material1955-77, undated (Box 111, Folder 5)
  - Clergy and Laymen Concerned about Vietnam/Clergy and Laity Concerned1967-82, undated (Box 111, Folder 6)
  - Comite de Servicio de los Amigos1962-79 (Box 111, Folder 7)
  - Committee for a Democratic Far East Policy/Far East Report/Maud Russell (Box 111)
    [see also SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE--Russell, Maud]
    - Mailings, flyers1945-64, undated (Box 111, Folder 8)
    - Newsletters and other publications1945-51, undated (Box 111, Folder 9)
  - Committee for Independent Political Action/Rhode Island Center for Political Action1966, undated (Box 111, Folder 10)
  - Committee for Non-Violent Action
    - Mailings, flyers, printed material1960-73, undated (Box 111, Folder 11)
    - Newsletters1960-68, undated (Box 111, Folder 12)
  - Committee for Peaceful Alternatives1949-51, undated (Box 111, Folder 13)
  - Committee for the Defense of Marion Bachrach1951-55, undated (Box 111, Folder 14)
  - Committee for World Development and World Disarmament1956-68, undated (Box 112, Folder 1)
  - Committee of First Amendment Defendants1959-61, undated (Box 112, Folder 2)
  - Committee to Aid the Monroe Defendants
    - Correspondence1962-63 (Box 112, Folder 3)
    - Printed material1961-64, undated (Box 112, Folder 4)
  - Committee to Defend America by Waging Peace1940, undated (Box 112, Folder 5)
  - Committee to Defend Resistance to Ghetto Life1970, undated (Box 112, Folder 6)
  - Committee to Defend the Panther 21/Panther Defense Committee1970, undated (Box 112, Folder 7)
  - Common Cause1971, 1977, undated (Box 112, Folder 8)
  - Common Council for American Unity1943-46, undated (Box 112, Folder 9)
  - Commonwealth College
    - Printed material1938-40, undated (Box 112, Folder 10)
    - Newsletters1940 (Box 112, Folder 11)
  - Commonwealth of World Citizens1919-56, undated (Box 112, Folder 12)
  - Communist Party1938, 1960-79, undated (Box 112, Folder 13)
  - Community Fund of Chicago1939-41, undated (Box 112, Folder 14)
  - Community Media Foundation1976 (Box 112, Folder 15)
  - Concerned Citizens for Justicecirca 1970-73 (Box 112, Folder 16)
  - Conference of Women for International Cooperation Year1962 (Box 112, Folder 17)
  - Congress of Industrial Organizations
    [see also oversize material for poster]
    - General1942-52, undated (Box 112, Folder 18-20)
    - Political Action Committee1938-47, undated (Box 112, Folder 21)
  - Congress of Racial Equality
    - Correspondence and printed material1954-67, undated (Box 113, Folder 1)
    - Rhode Island chapter1963-66 (Box 113, Folder 2)
  - Consumers Union/Consumers Technical Institute1944-74 (Box 113, Folder 3)
  - Council for a Livable World1963-72, undated (Box 113, Folder 4)
  - Council for Peace and Social Action1934-35, undated (Box 113, Folder 5)
  - C1938-84, undated (Box 113, Folder 6-8)
  - Defense Committee1969-74, undated (Box 113, Folder 7)
  - Democracy Unlimited1958-71, undated (Box 113, Folder 8)
  - Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee/ Democratic Socialists of America1975-80, undated (Box 114, Folder 1)
  - Descendents of the American Revolution1940-44, undated (Box 114, Folder 2)
  - Dissenting Democrats of Texas1968, undated (Box 114, Folder 3)
  - D1947-69, undated (Box 114, Folder 4)
  - Earl Robinson Foundation1981-83, undated (Box 114, Folder 5)
    [see also SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE-Friends and associates--Robinson, Earl and Helen; SERIES III. WRITINGS -Articles and essays-Alphabetical by subject-Robinson, Earl; and SERIES V. SUBJECT FILES--Robinson, Earl]
  - East and West Association1942-43 (Box 114, Folder 6)
  - Emergency Civil Liberties Committee
    [see also SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE--Friends and associates--Ferry, Elinor; Foreman, Clark]
    - Correspondence and printed material1951-79, undated (Box 114, Folder 7)
    - Newsletters1954-65 (Box 114, Folder 8)
  - End the Draft1962-65, undated (Box 114, Folder 9)
  - E1927-82 (Box 114, Folder 10)
  - Far East Reporter1948-71, undated (Box 114, Folder 11)
  - Fair Play for Cuba Committee
    - Miscellaneous printed material1961-63, undated (Box 114, Folder 12)
    - Newsletter1960-61, undated (Box 114, Folder 13)
  - Fellowship of Reconciliation
    - Correspondence and direct mailings1951-1980, undated (Box 115, Folder 1)
    - Printed material1938-70, undated (Box 115, Folder 2)
    - Newsletter1960-63 (Box 115, Folder 3)
    - New England/Boston1953-60 (Box 115, Folder 4)
    - Chicago/North Shore, Michigan and Rhode Island branches1954-65, undated (Box 115, Folder 5)
  - Flashlight1953-61 (Box 115, Folder 6)
  - Friends Committee on National Legislation1951-66, undated (Box 115, Folder 7)
  - Fund for Peace1970-80 (Box 115, Folder 8)
  - F1935-88, undated (Box 115, Folder 9)
  - General Strike for Peace1962-63 (Box 115, Folder 10)
  - Guardian (formally National Guardian)1949-88 (Box 115, Folder 11)
  - G1935-86, undated (Box 115, Folder 12)
  - The Haugs Report on the Cleveland Taft-Hartley Conspiracy Case1959-61 (Box 115, Folder 13)
  - Haymarket People's Fund and Rank and File Fund1977-88, undated (Box 115, Folder 14)
  - Help Unsell the Warundated (Box 116, Folder 1)
  - Highlander Folk School/Highlander Research and Education Center
    [see also SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE--Liveright, Herman and Betty]
    - Correspondence1946-1977 (Box 116, Folder 2)
    - Printed material1956-86, undated (Box 116, Folder 3)
  - Horizons Unlimited1957-58 (Box 116, Folder 4)
  - Hull House
    - Correspondence1939-74, undated (Box 116, Folder 5)
    - Printed material1937-76, undated (Box 116, Folder 6)
    - Cooperative1939-41, undated (Box 116, Folder 7)
    - Newsletters1939-44, undated (Box 116, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous1939-70, undated (Box 116, Folder 9)
  - Humanity Guildundated (Box 116, Folder 10)
  - H1940-88 (Box 116, Folder 11)
  - I.F. Stone's Weekly1953-67 (Box 116, Folder 12)
  - Illinois Labor History Society1986-88 (Box 116, Folder 13)
  - In These Times1978, 1988 (Box 116, Folder 14)
  - Independent Voters Leagueundated (Box 116, Folder 15)
  - Independent Voters of Americacirca 1944, undated (Box 116, Folder 16)
  - Infact1988 (Box 116, Folder 17)
  - International Disarmament Expedition of America1961 (Box 116, Folder 18)
  - International Labor Defense
    [see also Scottsboro Hernden Defense Fund]
    - Correspondence and printed material1935-44, undated (Box 116, Folder 19)
    - Newsletters1939-45 (Box 117, Folder 1)
    - Midwest Regional Office1939-40, undated (Box 117, Folder 2)
  - International Ladies Garment Workers Union1934-63, undated (Box 117, Folder 3)